Now another incredibly powerful debugging tool
还有一个非常强大的调试工具
that we're not really going to go over here.
在此我们不会详细介绍它
But it's important to know about because it can be really helpful
但了解一下它还是很重要的，因为它的用处真的很大
is that you can actually use console dot log in your solidity with hard hat.
你实际上可以在 Solidity 中使用 Hardhat 的 `console.log` 语句
If you're inside of a heart hat project,
如果你正处于一个 Hardhat 项目中
you just import hard hat slash console dot soul.
你只需要执行 `import "hardhat/console.sol"
And then right in your solidity, you can do console dot log,
然后在你的 Solidity 中，你就可以运行 `console.log`
and then type pretty much whatever you want.
并输入任何你想要的内容
When you execute these functions, similar to how we do a console dot log in JavaScript,
当你执行这些函数时，就和我们在 JavaScript 中使用 `console.log` 很相似
those will actually console dot log out to your terminal.
它们会把 `console.log` 的内容输出到你的终端上
Here's an example of if you run yarn, hard hat test
这里有一个例子，如果你运行 `yarn hardhat test`
and you have those console dot logs, you'll see stuff like this get printed out.
并且其中有包含 `console.log` 的语句，你就会看到类似这样的内容被打印出来
So in addition to the Visual Studio Code debugger,
所以除了使用 Visual Studio Code 的调试器之外
importing hard hat slash console dot Sol,
导入 `hardhat/console.sol`
and using console dot logs in your solidity can also be an effective debugging strategy.
并在 Solidity 中使用 `console.log` ，这同样也是一种有效的调试策略
Feel free to give this video a pause,
你可以暂停本视频
implement this in some of our contracts and try it out in our tests.
将其应用到我们的合约中，并在测试中尝试使用它